# TAYLOUR KROEKER

🤳 604-700-6116 | 🔷 taylour.em@gmail.com | 🗘 tailorem | 🗣 Vancouver, BC

## SUMMARY

Junior full-stack web developer excited by collaborative problem solving, creating beautiful, responsive interfaces and building efficient, maintainable systems. Continually seeking to strengthen my abilities as a developer, I revel in learning new concepts and applying best practices in my code. My 5 year history in the retail industry has encouraged my sense of dedication, persistence and enthusiasm, as well as strong interpersonal and organizational skills. When not at my keyboard, I'm usually painting, downhill skateboarding or discovering a new passion.

## **PROJECTS**

CrabbyApp - A real-time, multi-user chat application built with React, WebSockets and Express.

**Bendito** - Responsive, team-built food-ordering and order management app that communicates with clients via SMS. Personal contributions include coding the admin page functionality, initializing the database, menu-navbar responsiveness and implementing the overall visual layout. Built with **JavaScript**, **PostgreSQL**, **Express**, **Twilio API**, **AJAX**, **jQuery** and **HTML/CSS/SASS** with **Bootstrap**.

Relephant - A single-page Twitter-clone created using JavaScript, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, jQuery, AJAX and HTML/CSS and hosted on Heroku. Development focused on database integration and implementing AJAX with jQuery.

TinyApp - URL shortener built with Node.js, Express, HTML, EJS and CSS.

## **EDUCATION**

## Lighthouse Labs, Vancouver — Web Development

JUL 2018-SEP 2018

- Intensive full-stack web development bootcamp
- 500+ hours of mentor-assisted project-based programming
- Building apps using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, React, Ruby and more

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Omer DeSerres, Vancouver

Assistant Manager MAR 2017-JUL 2018 (& APR 2016-AUG 2016)

- Managed daily store operations and scheduling in a variable environment
- Trained and supported staff across multiple departments in floor service, receiving and framing
- Interacted and communicated daily with customers, staff, management, head office, and suppliers

#### Merchandiser JUL 2014-MAR 2017

- Created compelling displays through analysis of inventory and sales data
- Led full restructuring of store layout and assisted setup of new location
- Initiated development of consistent merchandising standards and store practices

#### Sales Associate OCT 2012-JUL 2014

- Encouraged customers to return by creating a welcoming atmosphere
- Utilized arts knowledge to assist customers in making informed decisions
- Showed attention to detail when operating POS system, maintaining store stock and cleanliness

## **Environmental Youth Alliance, Vancouver**

Youth Mentor JUL 2012-JUL 2013

- Guided youth at community-oriented events such as market plant-giveaways
- Prepared weekly informational materials and led activities to teach gardening skills
- Aided in maintenance of community garden space

## SKILLS

Languages JavaScript HTML5 CSS Rubu

Libraries & Frameworks
Node.js
Express.js
jQuery
AJAX
React & JSX

**Databases**MongoDB
PostgreSQL
Knex.js

VCS & Testing Git Mocha/Chai

Additional Photoshop Lightroom